RAYAN MOUSSALLEM

Madrid, Spain | (+961) 70 247 100 | rayanmoussallem@gmail.com | My LinkedIn | My GitHub | My Website French citizen

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Technology and entrepreneurship enthusiast and firm believer in continuous learning. Talented public speaker with solid interpersonal and team working skills. Adaptable and resilient candidate through years of diverse academic and professional experiences. Currently gearing up to create an impact in the world of big tech.

EDUCATION

IE University Madrid, Spain

Master in Computer Science & Business Technology

SEP. 2020 - JULY 2021

• Relevant Courses: Data Analytics, Python, Cloud Computing, AI & ML, Digital Business Strategy

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT

BEIRUT, LEBANON

Bachelor of Business Administration

Aug. 2017 - July 2020

- Concentration in Business Information and Decision Systems
- Relevant Courses: Pricing and Revenue Management, Enterprise System Design & Implementation
- AUB Tech Club: Monitored exciting tech news and authored 105+ "Weekly Trends" articles

STANFORD UNIVERSITY PALO ALTO, USA

International Honors Program (IHP)

JUNE 2019 – AUG. 2019

- Relevant Courses: Technology Entrepreneurship, Romancing the Room
- Startup Project: Led a cross-functional team to digitize student and faculty ID cards (IDentity)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ENDEAVOR BEIRUT DIGITAL DISTRICT, LEBANON

Intern (NGO, endeavorlebanon.org/)

May 2020 - July 2020

- Pitched 10 scale-up profiles to senior management out of which 7 were retained by the panel
- Led a comparative research about the scale-up ecosystems of Lebanon and Ireland that inspired management about several enhancements for the local model

ORCHID BEACH RESORT JIYEH, LEBANON

Quality and financial control officer (Luxury resort, orchid-lifestyle.com/)

JUNE 2018 - AUG. 2018

- Conducted strict daily quality control checks involving 20 different criteria to ensure optimal luxury experience
- Performed end of day sales reconciliation

DOMUS MANARA BEIRUT, LEBANON

Sales and marketing officer (Academic housing, domusmanara.com/)

DEC. 2017 - MAY 2018

- Designed and implemented social media campaigns that increased interactions by 60%
- Drafted a new rental contract that was adopted by the company
- Developed an all-new client database to digitize client records which improved access to time sensitive information

LANGUAGES

• Arabic (native) • English (native) • French (native)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Programming: Python, HTML, CSS, SQL, R, Git

- Oracle Autonomous DB: Certified Specialist
- AWS proficiency: VPC, EC2, RDS, Beanstalk Environment
- Excel: Advanced models for decision making

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

SIXTEENS JUNE 2013 – AUG. 2015

COFOUNDED A NOT-FOR-PROFIT AND RAISED FUNDS FOR A CHARITY 'OFFRE JOIE'

- Headed a team of 6 people to oversee the production of 4 goods categories to be sold
- Negotiated location rental fee of the retail outlet with the landlord in order to maximize profits

OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS

•	Elected class representative for my IE University master promotion	JAN. 2021
•	Management Excellence & Lean Six Sigma - Green Belt – Optness Institute	Nov. 2020
•	Google Certificates: Google Analytics, Data Studio, Google Cloud Infrastructure and Foundation	Nov. 2020
•	Taekwondo black belt	JUNE 2020
•	LAU Case Competition: Finalist with a team of four after solving four real life cases	Apr. 2019